April Only
Oh, yummy!
Springtime means cherry blossom sweets!
What do you want to do
for your birthday next week, Hananoi-kun?
It's the perfect time to go see the cherry
blossoms. How does that sound?
That sounds great! Are there any
good viewing spots around here?
Oh, this place might be nice.
It's kinda far, but it should
be walkable from here.
Recommended!
A hidden spot that even few locals know about.
It is somewhat far from the station, but that means
there aren't many tourists and you can relax and
enjoy flower viewing. Definitely worth a visit to see
the cherry blossoms floating in the river.
From exit 2 of the station, it's basically
a straight shot. It takes about 13 minutes
walking, but that'll give you a chance
to enjoy the scenery along the way.
Wow, that's so pretty!
Let's go there!
I guess I could... try making
a picnic lunch or something.
R-Really?
D-Don't expect too much, though.
I'm so happy!
I can't wait!
Episode 9
His First Birthday
Hello? Grandma?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm okay.
I still have some meals left, so don't worry.
Listen... I received a letter from Chizuru.
Oh, I got one too.
Mom and Dad say they aren't
coming home this spring.
Gracious. Do they even care
about their son's birthday?
So, what are you doing on the 6th?
If you don't have any plans, want to
come over? I'll cook you up a feast.
That's okay.
I'm planning to spend the day
with my girlfriend.
Oh, is that right?
Well, I suppose that's fine, then.
I know it's your birthday,
but don't get too carried away, okay?
You'd better be sure to send
her home at an early hour!
And it still gets cold at night,
so wear something warm—
Hinase Hotaru
The weekly forecast says
the 6th should be sunny!
I'm so glad!
I've never been so excited about a
birthday before. This is a first for me.
Hananoi
Thanks for today
The scones were delicious!
The weekly forecast says
the 6th should be sunny!
I'm so glad!
The sakura trees should be
in full bloom too. I can't wait.
Hmm.
A present, a picnic lunch...
I wonder if there's anything else I can do.
It's the perfect opportunity. I want to do
something to make him super happy.
One day,
when we finally share a real kiss,
I want you to be as elated as I will be.
So when your heart is ready for it
and you decide you want it,
give me a signal, okay?
A signal...
No, wait! He was saying I should think
about it without feeling pressured, right?
But still, if he asks me if
I want to kiss him again...
I'm not sure I get it.
When he kissed my forehead,
I felt more embarrassed than anything.
What makes people want
to kiss in the first place?
So, considering the situation,
what wisdom might you be able
to share with me, Big Sis?
Why does this kid keep coming
to me for advice like that?
I'm sorry to bother you.
But I'm way too embarrassed
to ask my friends.
Oh, kissing? Yeah, that's easy. Listen up.
When you like someone, you want
to be close to them, right?
It's the next step from that.
I see.
I think.
Not that I'd know.
So a kiss is the next step up
from wanting to touch him?
Oh, Hotaru.
Remember the memorial service we've been
planning for Grandpa? It'll be on the 6th.
Yeah? I guess it is that time of year.
Oh, wait. Do you mean April 6th?
Yup.
Sorry! Wh-What should we do?
I thought I was free!
Hmm, well, you've got the memorial service.
You probably won't be in the
mood to celebrate anyway.
Let's do it another day.
But I don't have any other days off when the
cherry blossoms will still be in bloom.
And school's starting soon.
It's okay.
As long as we can celebrate
together, Hotaru-chan,
the time and place don't matter.
I'm still going to be happy.
Well, Hotaru, you didn't know Grandpa
that well. You don't have to go.
No. I'll go.
Are you sure?
It is what it is...
Dismiss
Snooze
April 6
Alarm
Hananoi-kun,
happy birthday!
Thanks
Okay.
What'll I do today?
I've pretty much finished up here.
I guess I'll go check it out by myself.
Maybe I can bring her here next year.
Wow, that looks good!
Takoyaki
I didn't know they had food stands.
Well, this one is on me.
Thank you! I was craving some takoyaki.
Really? It's your lucky day.
There aren't many people
over here by the river.
Ah, it's finally over!
Watch it, Tomo!
It took two hours to get here by train.
If we leave before it gets dark, I might
still have a little time to see him.
U-Um, Mom?
Hmm?
What's next?
Next, the plan is to go to
a hotel for dinner with everyone.
It's guaranteed to be night
before we get back!
What's got you so anxious, Hotaru?
Well, to tell you the truth...
today is my boyfriend's birthday.
Then why not leave already?
Huh?
You're in high school.
You can find your way back, right?
B-But...
It'll just be adults blabbing after this.
There's no reason the kids have to be there.
I'll make up some excuse to tell Dad.
Is that really okay?
You know, you've seemed a lot
happier lately, Hotaru.
Tomo and I are so loud,
it always felt like you were holding back.
But you should be able to do
what you want, too.
Grandpa wouldn't want to see you sad,
either. Don't you think you should go?
I mean, it's his birthday.
You only get your day once a year.
I feel like those twenty-four hours
should be totally dedicated to you.
It should be a super special time for him.
And... I'm only just now realizing that.
Yeah, I bet.
If you make it a special day,
I'm sure he'll love that.
Sis! I... I really have to go today!
Roger that.
Leave things here to me.
Sis, you really are the best!
Happy birthday, Hotaru-chan.
I hope today turned out
to be special for you.
But it had to be today. I wanted you to know
that today is the most
special day in the world.
Me too!
Hananoi-kun!
Hello.
Hey, Hananoi? It's me, Kurata!
How the hell did you get my number?
Oh, come on! You forgot already?
I asked you to call me
when I lost my phone in class!
You forced me to.
You saved my butt, man!
And then you secretly saved my number?
No big deal.
Actually, I wanted to ask you something
about our spring break homework.
Oh, also, I heard from Hibiki.
Isn't today your birthday?
Happy birthday, man!
And let me guess.
Are you hanging with Hinase-san?
No, I'm not.
Wait, what? No way! That's so sad!
Dude, would you lay off it?
What? But this is your first birthday
with her. That's gotta hurt.
Hotaru-chan had something else going on.
If we can celebrate some other
time, that's good enough.
Wow, maybe you are a good guy.
You always come off so possessive,
but I guess you know when to back off.
I underestimated you!
I'm hanging up.
Hey, wait! The homework!
What part of me is a "good guy"?
Oh, a butterfly!
You're right! It sure is pretty.
Yeah!
How have you
Are you doing
Is Grandma
It's time to go!
Okay!
I've been trying to find
someone who needs me.
More than family, more than a friend.
I was looking for someone who
would always put me first.
I would've done anything
for someone like that.
But even when I give all my love to people,
they never put me first.
And if I can't be their number one,
then what's the point?
That's all I ever think about.
How does that make me a "good guy"?
Still, I don't know why,
but when I'm with Hotaru-chan,
there are moments when I stop
caring about being number one.
Her smile is enough for me.
That alone makes me feel complete.
I want you to keep smiling.
Don't look at anyone else.
I don't want you to hate me.
Don't leave me.
My feelings... I'm a mess.
Hotaru-chan
Hananoi-kun, where are you?
H-He isn't here.
I couldn't get him on the phone
either. Where could he be?
Weird. It's usually the other way around.
It's always Hananoi-kun
who comes running to look for me.
I don't want you to leave me behind.
Hananoi
Hananoi-kun,
where are you?
I'm at home
Huh?!
Why would he lie about where he is?
I won't leave you behind.
I won't leave you behind!
Hananoi-kun,
where are you?
I'm at home
I'm on my way now
Oh! Huh? Should I go home?
I'm at home
Hinase Hotaru
I'm on my way now
Stay right where you are!
Hinase Hotaru
I'm on my way now
Stay right where you are!
This time I'm
gonna find you!
How...?
Oh!
Hananoi-kun!
How?
Ow... ow, ow.
S-Sorry!
But I found you!
A-Are you okay?! Are you hurt?
Did you hit anything?
No, I'm okay! You caught me, Hananoi-kun.
But, Hotaru-chan, the memorial service...
I snuck out partway through.
Huh?
Um, I realized it had to be today.
Happy birthday, Hananoi-kun!
You always make me so happy. Thank you!
How is it that you're always...
like this?
I love you so much!
I want to be your number one.
But... you don't have to put me first.
As long as you stay with me forever...
Thank you, Hotaru-chan.
That's all I need.
The cherry blossoms sure are pretty.
Yeah.
There's hardly any point
in seeing them alone.
Hey, Hananoi-kun, I can tell
you're trying to act normal,
but was today really hard for you?
Uh...
I mean, it'd be a little difficult for me
to stay with you all of the time,
but whenever you aren't doing okay,
I definitely want to be with you.
If you ever feel like that,
just call me, okay?
Promise me.
Will I really be able to
keep a smile on her face going forward?
Wow!
It's a cherry blossom blizzard!
Can a guy like me be with Hotaru-chan?
Is that even allowed?
No, I can do this.
I'm not the boy who couldn't
do anything for her anymore.
From now on,
I won't run away, no matter what.
I'll stay and protect this
girl from whatever happens.
I want to be your soulmate.